SIVA NARAYANA REDDY

Associate - Spring Boot MicroServices Developer



SUMMARY

Fast paced Spring Developer with 5 years of experience on the very latest versions of spring modules and Java 8.

Good knowledge of Design Patterns and Concurrency API. Looking for challenging roles like a technical lead to mentor rookies and working towards high quality delivery in Java and Cloud space.



Dollar Center, Chennai



+91-9087140888



narayana-sambireddy@outlook.com



github.com/narayana-sambireddy



linkedin.com/in/narayana-sambireddy



youtube.com/narayana-sambireddy



facebook.com/narayana-sambireddy

INTERESTS

Mythologies & Entrepreneurship ideas

STRENGTHS

Trustworthy & Straight-forward

INSPIRATION

My Dad & Mom

SIGNIFICANT ACHIEVEMENTS

- Star performer at Apple Account
- ❖ Kick-started and driven a critical project from E2E and delivered an impregnable quality product.

EDUCATION

2012 – 2016 Master of Software Engineering BITS PILANI

Pursued Masters degree while working at Wipro

AREA OF EXPERTISE

JAVA [1.8]

Working on the latest version of Java with all the latest features of functional programming aligned with Object Oriented design.

SPRING PLATFORM [4+] & SPRING-BOOT [1.5.2.RELEASE]

Real-time web development experience in the below spring modules: webmvc, data-jpa, security, SpEL, aop, batch, integration, boot and cloud.

Used Hibernate as Vendor Adapter for Oracle database.

MICROSERVICES

Implemented MicroServices approach to accelerate delivery by minimizing communication and coordination between the teams while reducing the scope and risk of change.

DOCKER CONTAINERIZATION

Implemented continuous delivery pipeline with Docker, Jenkins, GitHub and AWS AMI's

APACHE CASSANDRA

Hands-on experience on Cassandra and worked on multiple use cases for Apple online store data modelling and integrating with Java / Spring.

CONTINUOUS INTEGRATION/DELIVERY

Implementation experience on Jenkins, Sonar, JIRA, Stash and Bamboo.

WORK HISTORY

Aug 2012 - Mar 2017 Wipro Technologies

Client:



1. BRUCKE PLATFORM

DESCRIPTION:

Brücke enables various business processes and functions to operate on an integrated platform. Various groups in and out of Apple Online Store can take advantage of Brücke's Security, Messaging and reusable components to support their business.

BRÜCKE ADMIN:

- Authentication via Apple Connect
- API and Admin console for Module specific authorization

BRÜCKE MESSAGING CLIENT (BMC):

- Common Interface for Solace and Geneva
- Multi-Threaded Publishing
- Multi-Threaded Consumer
- Queue Browser: View and Count Messages
- Delete Messages (Selective and All)
- Message Acknowledgment Support

BRÜCKE CORE:

- All Database Related configuration
- Entity and Repository mapping
- Includes Espresso Ticketing feature to raise Alerts.

BRÜCKE FEED PROCESSOR:

- Consumer implementation of BMC
- Designed to consume messages from given endpoint and process them
- The statistics are published to Cassandra Database.
- Multiple Microservice implementations each of a specific processing logic.

ROLE: Developer L1 & L2 (Java & Spring)

RESPONSIBILITIES & CONTRIBUTION:

- Built reusable components and libraries for future use across entire Online Store.
- Completely involved into developing the application with Spring and Maven.
- Written unit and integration test cases using spring-test and mockito.
- Configured Jenkins & Sonar on AWS EC2 for CI & CD.

2. QUOTE MACHINE / QUOTES CENTRAL

DESCRIPTION:

QuoteMachine is the master data management tool for CommitCode (Shipping Availability) and NPI Readiness Events. It is the system for assigning initial quotes (Shipping Availability) for products for a NPI.

The goals of this tool are as follows.

- ❖ Simplify the Commit Code setup including all messaging, translations and related master data to support all corresponding systems execution during NPI readiness events.
- ❖ Collect all the relevant master data into one management system which allows for a comprehensive setup and validation process.
- ❖ Decrease the time to production for creating, updating and disseminating information to downstream execution systems.
- ❖ Increase the reporting and confirmation processes to ensure correct data management.
- ❖ Overall, reduce error in the business process.

ROLE: Senior Project Engineer (Java & Spring)

RESPONSIBILITIES & CONTRIBUTION:

- Kick-started the project from scratch which involved modules viz. QuoteMachineService, QMSCore, QMSStatsCollectorService.
- Independently started, developed and written the entire QMSStatsCollectorService component, which listens to Queue (amq/solace) endpoints for messages and processes with the provided processing logic.
- Independently developed the entire module of QMSCassandraCore.
- Migrated the source from Java 7 to Java 8 and did refactoring wherever necessary.
- The entire application was written in Spring and Java8.
- Migrated the source from Java 7 to Java 8 and did refactoring wherever necessary.
- Done release cut for the project through jgit plugin.

TOKEN OF APPRECIATION:

- * Received lot of accolades from the client and Wipro Management.
- * Received a sum of \$1000 USD as a token of appreciation for the work accomplished from the client manager.

Apr 2017 – Present Cognizant Technology Solutions

Client: verizon√

3. Distributed Vision Systems (DVS): Order Re-Wire

DESCRIPTION:

Verizon being the 3rd largest customer of IBM's Mainframe Systems and paying a huge sum for the infrastructure and support has lately realized it is time to move on and started liberating itself from the clutches of legacy and monolithic systems by focusing on Open Source Frameworks and MicroSerivces and Cloud space.

The end goal of the assignment is to bring down the MIPS of the Vision (mainframe system).

ROLE: Senior Analyst (Java & Spring)

RESPONSIBILITIES & CONTRIBUTION:

- Reverse engineer the mainframe schema and replicate the closest possible Cassandra Schema (keyspaces with similar tables).
- Need to break down the existing monolithic services that are interacting with Vision Systems.
- Implement Mircoservices for the identified APIs using spring boot.
- Compose Docker file for the microservice to build docker images.
- Converting DB2/Vision queries into Cassandra queries leveraging TypeDef framework written in groovy.
- Implement Service Discovery using Eureka for collaboration between Mircoservices.